



## Alex Buijs

+316 4048 5702 contact@alexbuijsweb.nl <a href="http://alexbuijsweb.nl">http://alexbuijsweb.nl</a> Haïtidreef 3E, 3563 HC, Utrecht

## **Profile**

Alex Buijs (17-05-1974) is a developer with over 8 years of experience creating web applications. He gains much satisfaction from programming in Ruby. In january 2014 he started as a freelancer, developing web applications with Ruby on Rails. He enjoys using the latest techniques and adhering to best practices. He takes pride in creating beautiful and minimal code. Alex is a team player and is used to work on Agile/SCRUM driven projects for larger organisations. He believes in high quality software best practices such as Test Driven Development and Behaviour Driven Development.

## Experience

MOBILE APP DEVELOPER, SEACON (KABISA), WEERT - 2014/04-2014/05

For Seacon Logistics, a customer of Kabisa, Alex made a cross platform mobile application with Cordova (PhoneGap). The application is basically a single-page HTML5 web application, wrapped in a native WebView.

Techniques used: Rails (for it's asset pipeline and backend API), Backbone, Marionette, Bootstrap, Coffeescript, SASS, Git.

MOBILE APP DEVELOPER, IDT (KABISA), WEERT - 2014/02-2014/04

For IDT, a customer of Kabisa, Alex made a cross platform mobile application with Cordova (PhoneGap). The application is basically a single-page HTML5 web application, wrapped in a native WebView.

Techniques used: Rails (for it's asset pipeline), Backbone, Emblem, Foundation, Coffeescript, SASS, Git.

**WEB DEVELOPER, ULTIMAKER (KABISA), GELDERMALSEN – 2013/10-2014/02**For Ultimaker, a customer of Kabisa, Alex contributed to <u>YouMagine.com</u>, a social platform for sharing 3D print designs.

Techniques used: Ruby on Rails, Coffeescript, SASS, Slim, Bootstrap, PostgreSQL, Redis, Test Driven Development, Heroku, Git.

WEB DEVELOPER, MALMBERG (CIBER), DEN BOSCH – 2013/01-2013/10 & 2012/04-2012/07 & 2008/10-2012/02

For Malmberg, a customer of Ciber, Alex contributed over several periods of time, to the creation and expansion of the Malmberg Publishing Platform, a new generation of teaching methods.

Techniques used: Ruby on Rails, Coffeescript, Haml, SASS, SQL Server, Apache, Passenger, Capistrano, Git.

WEB DEVELOPER, PHILIPS (CIBER), EINDHOVEN - 2012/07-2013/01

For Philips, a customer of Ciber, Alex contributed to the creation of <u>light-collector.com</u>, a social platform for sharing images.

Techniques used: Ruby on Rails, Coffeescript, Haml, SASS, PostgreSQL, Amazon S2, Nginx, Unicorn, Capistrano, Git.

MOBILE APP DEVELOPER, PHILIPS (CIBER), EINDHOVEN - 2012/02-2012/04

For Philips, a customer of Ciber, Alex contributed to the creation of the cross-platform mobile application Lighting Hub. It is used for browsing the entire Philips Lighting Catalogue.

Techniques used: Titanium, Coffeescript, SQLite, Git.

WEB DEVELOPER, CIBER, EINDHOVEN - 2005/02-2008/10

Customers during this period include: CVZ (Diemen), Zwolle Municipality (Zwolle), Radio Netherlands Worldwide (Hilversum), Equens (Utrecht), Ministry of the Interior and Kingdom Relations (The Hague), ABN AMRO (Amsterdam).

Techniques used: Java Enterprise Edition, Hibernate, Struts, Maven, Subversion, Oracle DB, SQL Server, MySQL, WebSphere, Liferay, Tomcat, JBoss, Adobe LiveCycle, Apache, IIS.

## Education

Alex received his Master's degree Cognitive Artificial Intelligence at the Faculty of Philosophy, Utrecht University in 2001.